Bee Hwa, Siew

<u>LinkedIn: @Vivien Siew</u>
<u>Website: Github @viviensiu</u>

Email: viviensiu@gmail.com
Phone (UK): +44-075088-99310

SUMMARY

A Masters in Computer Science graduate, certified Data Scientist with a diverse project portfolio and experienced IT Project Manager in Banking Payments system over 10 years. A problem solver, highly motivated, resourceful and independent with a flair of task prioritization plus critical time-management skills. Possess excellent communication skills especially in bridging understanding between technical and non-technical stakeholders.

EDUCATION

• University Science of Malaysia

Master of Science in Computer Science

Penang, MY
Graduated in 2009

• University Putra of Malaysia
Bachelor of Computer Science (Multimedia)

Selangor, MY Graduated in 2005

Professional Certification

• MITx 18.6501x: Fundamentals of Statistics: 2022

• MITx 6.86x: Machine Learning with Python-From Linear Models to Deep Learning: 2022

• MITx 6.00.1x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python: 2022

• MITx 6.431x: Probability - The Science of Uncertainty and Data: 2022

• Data Scientist Professional (DataCamp): 2021

• AI Singapore: AI for Industry (Foundations in AI): 2021

• Project Management Professional (PMP): 2019

Data Science Projects Portfolio

- Ocean energy efficiency data challenge: using Scotland's energy performance data, I generate rankings and top 5 lists, discover correlations between building features and energy performances, build algorithms to predict energy cost and recommend building modifications for energy cost savings.
- Major incidents analysis in UK year 2020: Using Plotly, I identified the most important factors for major incidents and plot incident hotspots using a combination of address retrieval via Geopy and geospatial plotting via Geopandas.
- <u>Used cars pricing prediction</u>: Using Linear Regression modeling, hyperparameter-tuning and R2 scoring, I predicted used cars pricing with a best R2 score of 0.9538 and over 90% predictions that meet the pricing baseline.
- Bankruptcy Risk Prediction with Taiwan Economic Journal (TEJ) Data: Using EDA, hypothesis testing and classification modeling, I achieved a best result of only 7 False Negatives in the bankruptcy prediction model.
- Misogynist classification on Urban Dictionary content: Using NLP techniques and classification modeling, I classified misogynistic and non-misogynistic texts on Urban Dictionary data with a best score of 0.87.
- Singapore Taxi availability prediction: Using GeoJSON, Regression modeling and RMSE evaluation on results, I predicted taxi availability across different times and regions, with a 9-15% deviation from actual results.
- ICU mortality rate classification using APACHE IV data: Prediction on ICU patients mortality rate with classification model (DecisionTreeClassifier) with a ROC-AUC scoring of 0.519.
- Lending Club Loan Data Analysis: With the goal to maximize profit while minimize potential losses, I analyzed loan data with EDA and proposed an investment portfolio for moderate risk investors that generates 9-13% returns and repayment improvement from 83.9% to 86.8%.
- Wine Promotion Analysis for Russia drinks company: Using Unsupervised Learning methods with Silhouette Scores metrics, I identified and proposed 10 other Russian regions for a wine promotion campaign using the previous successful promotion in Saint Petersburg as a baseline.

- Programming Languages: : Python, SQL, AS400 RPGLE, Java, HTML
- Data Science Skills & Packages: Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, Statistical Analysis, Hypothesis Testing, Data mining, Data Visualization (EDA), Data Analytics, Geospatial visualization (Geopandas, Geopy), Natural Language Processing (NLP), Web scraping, Machine Learning modeling (Linear Regression, Classification, Clustering, Unsupervised Learning).
- Others: Project management, Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), Change management, Vendor management, Business analysis.

Work Experience

• Sumitomo Mitsui Bank Corporation

Singapore

Assistant Vice President, IT Steering Group (ISG)

July 2016 - Aug 2019

- o Contributions: Lead, manage a team of 10-15 vendors and 20-30 business users in strategic and regulatory regional payments project management: Sydney BPAY, Manila Metrobank Collection, Seoul Swift Auto Repair, Manila TEMS enhancement 2019.
- Other responsibilities: change management and business analysis for system enhancements & production support for regional Payment systems in Manila, Sydney and Seoul.

• United Overseas Bank

Singapore

 $IT\ Manager$

Oct 2011 - June 2016

- o Contributions: Bulk payment team (ROS) project lead, coordinator for 2 contractors and 5-10 business users in strategic and regulatory project management: FAST (G3) Project Phase 1 - Phase 2, Regional BIB plus project.
- Other responsibilities: Perform business analysis, system enhancements and production support for bulk payment, cheque, direct debit and remittance processing back-end system.

• Overseas Chinese Bank Corporation

Kuala Lumpur, MY July 2009 - Sept 2011

IT Manager • Contributions: Project lead and business analyst for IBG and Giro Plus system.

• Other responsibilities: System enhancement and production support for payments system.

• HSBC

Kuala Lumpur, MY

Oct 2006 - June 2008

o Contributions: Programmer for systems: Interest Bearing Scheme (DIBS), Cheque Truncation system (CTCS), Islamic Subsidiary.

• Scope International

IT Project Officer

Kuala Lumpur, MY

Programmer

Oct 2005 - June 2006

• Contributions: Programmer for Standard Chartered MY e-Statement project.